Send to Amazon is a multi-step workflow
for shipping products to Amazon for distribution
with the FBA program.
To access Send to Amazon in the Seller Central Main menu,
click Inventory and select Shipments.
At the top of the shipping queue page,
hover over the Shipments dropdown menu
and select Send to Amazon.
First, you'll set the address that you want to ship from
and the Marketplace destination.
These details can't be changed
after you complete Send to Amazon step two.
You can choose from two options for selecting SKUs.
Select from List or File Upload.
With either method, you may ship case packs,
individual units or a combination of both.
If you choose Select from List,
you'll see a list of all your SKUs
that have been converted to FBA.
If you have created any case pack templates,
you can select the filter, only show SKUs with case pack template.
First, let's look at adding case packs.
If you're shipping boxes with one or more units
of the same SKU, case pack templates save your packing details
so you won't have to re-enter them
every time you ship that SKU.
To start, choose the template you want to use
and input how many boxes you plan to ship.
If you have remaining individual units
that don't fit into your current case pack template,
you can select more inputs.
Click Ready to Send to add the case pack to the shipment.
You can repeat this process for as many case packs you need.
To add products as individual units,
select individual units.
Then enter information about the prep and labeling
of each unit.
Enter the number of units of that product you intend to ship
and click Ready to Pack.
If you choose File Upload,
you can upload a file with the list of SKUs
you want to replenish.
To create the template,
select from a list of customization options.
Then select Generate and Download Template.
Be sure to enter all of the required information
for each SKU.
Save your file as an Excel file.
xlsx
or as a tab delimited file.
txt and upload it.
If there are no errors in the file,
we will populate the SKUs
in the SKUs Ready to Send tab for you to review.
Whether you selected SKUs from a list or uploaded a file,
review your selections in the SKUs Ready to Send tab
to ensure everything is correct.
If you selected Seller as the labeling owner
of any of your units,
you will notice the Print SKU labels link
at the bottom of your SKUs Ready to Send list.
These are different from packing labels,
which you will print later.
Print the SKU labels and apply them to each unit.
If you selected Amazon as the labeling owner,
skip this step.
Your confirmation button will look different
depending on the contents of your shipment.
If your shipment contains only case packs,
click Confirm and Continue to move on to step two,
Confirm Shipping.
If your shipment contains any individual units,
click Pack Individual Units to continue.
This will bring up step one B,
which walks you through packing
and labeling the individual units in your shipment.
It's important to pack your SKUs
according to the pack groups listed in this step.
Knowing the contents of each box
allows us to move your inventory through our network
and make your inventory available for sale faster.
For each packing group,
determine if everything will fit in one box
or if multiple boxes will be needed.
If only one box is needed,
input box dimensions and weight.
If you select multiple boxes,
you have a few choices
for how you would like to upload box information.
You can upload information in a web form,
Excel file or with scan and pack
if you have a mix of individual units and case packs.
You can also utilize 2D barcodes
or have Amazon manually process box contents for a fee
as long as you have no case pack templates in your shipment.
Read the descriptions for each option
to determine what works best for your shipment.
As you pack, make sure to label your boxes.
For example, Pack Group 2, Box 3.
This will make matching shipping labels
to the correct box much easier.
Once you have completed packing all individual units
and uploaded box information,
click Confirm and Continue to move on to step two,
Confirm Shipping.